<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Comic Book Murals</string>
    <string name="str_tv_about_title_comicbook">History of the comic book murals</string>
    <string name="str_tv_about_content_comicbook">"The comic book mural route began in the early 1990s. The City of Brussels went against the large publicity billboards that were polluting the city centre. However, when thise signs were all removed, quite a few walls were left behind neglected and in need of repair. Thus was born the first comic book mural: the character Ragebol from the Brussels based comic book artist Frank Pé in the Plattesteen district. A fine initiative where art and urban renewal meet was soon followed up on. A number of authors in Brussels were immediately set to work on the capital city’s walls.  Throughout the years, the route became diverse and plentiful, and non-Brussels Belgian authors collaborated on it… And soon also some foreign authors – Hugo Pratt, Zep, Dupuy-Berberian, Uderzo and Mezzo among them – who are part of the massive influences exerted by the Belgian-French comic book tradition.  From Tintin to Spirou, across Corto Maltese, Lucky Luke, Yoko Tsuno, Natasha, Asterix… Today nearly sixty characters adorn the walls along a walk that leaves behind the touristy roads and leaves you to discover a side of Brussels full of charm and authenticity. Presently, the comic book mural route is developing further still. The world of comic books has grown more diverse and the murals modernise along with it. Graphic novels and niches conquer the walls with artists such as Nix, Dominique Goblet and Brecht Evens. "</string>
    <string name="str_btn_home_about">About the comic book mural route</string>
    <string name="str_btn_home_map">Map of comic book murals</string>
<!--    <string name="str_btn_home_routes">Suggested routes</string>-->
    <string name="str_lp_pref_sort">Sorting options</string>
    <string name="str_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="str_app_bar_search">Search</string>
    <string name="str_btn_home_list">List of comic book murals</string>
    <string name="str_pref_sort_name">Sort by character name/title</string>
    <string name="str_pref_sort_artist">Sort by artist</string>
    <string name="str_btn_show_on_map">Show on map</string>
    <string name="str_no_year">year unknown</string>
    <string name="str_no_artist">Anonymous</string>
    <string name="str_no_character_title">Untitled</string>
    <string name="str_tv_about_title_streetart">History of the street art route</string>
    <string name="str_request_mural_dialog_posbtn">Send email</string>
    <string name="str_request_mural_dialog_negbtn">Cancel</string>
    <string name="str_request_mural_email_client">Choose your email client</string>
    <string name="str_request_mural_dialog_title">Request mural</string>
    <string name="str_request_mural_email_subject">New request for comic book mural</string>
    <string name="str_tv_request_mural_dialog_content">Do you own real estate within the City of Brussels and would you like a comic book mural on a wall of your building? Send us an email to find out whether this is possible for you.</string>
    <string name="str_btn_home_gallery">Photo gallery</string>
    <string name="str_tv_about_content_streetart">"Karine Lalieux became alderman of Culture in December 2012 and announced her intention to develop a PARCOURS Street Art.\\n  As of January 2013, she meets with the actors of the Street Art world through the Brussels Creative Forum and different festivals, dedicated to urban art. Most artist who are active in the capital city and the big Belgian collectives are inventoried. The meetings multiplied and the conclusions confirmed the basic hypothesis: the Belgian street art scene has to be made visible, has to receive room for expression and has to be financially supported in order to work professionally. \\n  In addition, Street Art complies with all of the cultural targets that Karine Lalieux presents to the College for the 2012-2018 term: \\n -\tDecentralisation: frescos in all of the neighbourhoods, culture for the public. \\n -\tAccessibility: there are no conditions to admire a mural and there are no admission fees either, since it is an outdoor museum. \\n -\tConnectivity: street artists have different backgrounds (graffiti, visual art, graphic design, self-taught…).\\n -\tSupport of the artistic employment: through different cultural events and locations, the city had signed nearly 2000 artistic contracts during the past 6 years. \\n\\n  Street art is ‘hip’, everyone asks these artists to animate events with live paintings, to decorate buildings of offices… but a budget is seldom present, as well as a lack of coherency. \\n   Therefore the Cabinet of Culture has decided to delve into the matter and to position itself as a real hub in Brussels. \\n  In 2014, Karine Lalieux negotiates with the Collegiate Body  on the yearly budget of 100.000 Euro to produce frescos of contemporary urban art and eventually they have mapped out a route, following the example of the comic strip murals across the city of Brussels. \\n  As of 2014, the first murals will start to appear. Calls for projects, assignments, free speech murals and other collaborations succeed one another. \\n  Initially, local artists will sign the first contracts, but the city will open up to international artists as well, especially when their reputation aids the Route’s and the upcoming artists’ visibility. \\n As of December 2016, an open call was made to owners to draw up a list of walls that could possibly be used by street artists. The operation turns out to be a success and enables the Culture Department to save valuable time during the development of this route. Private operators (large companies or ‘small’ private owners), but public organisations (schools, authorities, city developers) too, apply and help create beautiful projects. \\n In 2017, a logo was designed for the route and it received an identity: we now call it PARCOURS (in capital letters).  \\n\\n PARCOURS has a website, which incorporates all of the executed projects, offers an explanation about every work of art and presents the artists. The site offers walks for every neighbourhood and every mural is localised so your smartphone can guide you from mural to mural. It also contains current calls for submitting new projects and a news feed. This site is PARCOURSstreetart.brussel and is self-service for all residents, tourists or tourist guides. \\n With all of this material, about a hundred produced or co-produced works, the PARCOURS-team will use this winter to work out future prospects: a paper map, guided tours, awareness-raising workshops, innovating and experimental projects. All of this is meant to put Brussels on the European map of Street Art. \\n The goal that the alderman of Culture had set in 2012, gradually seems to be reached: strengthening the urban art scene, the upcoming and professional, Brussels, Belgian and international art scene, at first by means of mural art and subsequently through other media. The press starts to talk about it and the Street Art movement knows that there is an open door to launch, mentor or support new projects. \\n There really is a place in Brussels for spontaneous Street Art.  "</string>
    </resources>