<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Comic Book Murals</string>
    <string name="str_tv_about_title_comicbook">History of the comic book murals</string>
    <string name="str_tv_about_content_comicbook">"The comic book mural route began in the early 1990s. The City of Brussels went against the large publicity billboards that were polluting the city centre. However, when thise signs were all removed, quite a few walls were left behind neglected and in need of repair. Thus was born the first comic book mural: the character Ragebol from the Brussels based comic book artist Frank Pé in the Plattesteen district. A fine initiative where art and urban renewal meet was soon followed up on. A number of authors in Brussels were immediately set to work on the capital city’s walls.  Throughout the years, the route became diverse and plentiful, and non-Brussels Belgian authors collaborated on it… And soon also some foreign authors – Hugo Pratt, Zep, Dupuy-Berberian, Uderzo and Mezzo among them – who are part of the massive influences exerted by the Belgian-French comic book tradition.  From Tintin to Spirou, across Corto Maltese, Lucky Luke, Yoko Tsuno, Natasha, Asterix… Today nearly sixty characters adorn the walls along a walk that leaves behind the touristy roads and leaves you to discover a side of Brussels full of charm and authenticity. Presently, the comic book mural route is developing further still. The world of comic books has grown more diverse and the murals modernise along with it. Graphic novels and niches conquer the walls with artists such as Nix, Dominique Goblet and Brecht Evens. "</string>
    <string name="str_btn_home_about">About the comic book mural route</string>
    <string name="str_btn_home_map">Map of comic book murals</string>
    <string name="str_btn_home_routes">Suggested routes</string>
    <string name="str_lp_pref_sort">Sorting options</string>
    <string name="str_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="str_app_bar_search">Search</string>
    <string name="str_btn_home_list">List of comic book murals</string>
    <string name="str_pref_sort_name">Sort by character name/title</string>
    <string name="str_pref_sort_artist">Sort by artist</string>
</resources>